Rin.
Utw
Presents
Kurikaesu sekai nando te wo nobashitara
繰り返す世界 何度手を伸ばしたら
How many times must I reach my hand out to this repeating world
Kurikaesu sekai nando te wo nobashitara
繰り返す世界 何度手を伸ばしたら
How many times must I reach my hand out to this repeating world
Hakanai namida wa kuroi kokoro tokasu no
儚い涙は黒い心溶かすの？
For the fleeting tears to soften my black heart?
Hakanai namida wa kuroi kokoro tokasu no
儚い涙は黒い心溶かすの？
For the fleeting tears to soften my black heart?
Mebaedashita omoi ga mune ni hibiita nara
芽生え出した思いが胸に響いたなら
If these awakened feelings resonated in my heart
Mebaedashita omoi ga mune ni hibiita nara
芽生え出した思いが胸に響いたなら
If these awakened feelings resonated in my heart
Kimi no tonari de zutto kawarazu mamoru darou
君の隣でずっと変わらず護るだろう
I'd stand guard beside you forever and ever
Kimi no tonari de zutto kawarazu mamoru darou
君の隣でずっと変わらず護るだろう
I'd stand guard beside you forever and ever
Ochita kibou wo hirotte
堕ちた希望を拾って
If I could pick up these fallen hopes
Ochita kibou wo hirotte
堕ちた希望を拾って
If I could pick up these fallen hopes
Asu ni tsunaide yukeba
明日に繋いでゆけば
And link them on to tomorrow
Asu ni tsunaide yukeba
明日に繋いでゆけば
And link them on to tomorrow
Karamatta ibitsu na negai datte hodokeru
絡まった歪な願いだってほどける
Even these entwined, twisted wishes will come apart
Karamatta ibitsu na negai datte hodokeru
絡まった歪な願いだってほどける
Even these entwined, twisted wishes will come apart
Hikari wo kazashite tamerai wo keshita
光をかざして躊躇いを消した
I've held up the light and erased my hesitation
Hikari wo kazashite tamerai wo keshita
光をかざして躊躇いを消した
I've held up the light and erased my hesitation
Agetakatta no wa mirai de
あげたかったのは未来で
What I wanted to give you is in the future
Agetakatta no wa mirai de
あげたかったのは未来で
What I wanted to give you is in the future
Naiteru yoru daita mama
泣いてる夜抱いたまま
Crying and embracing the night
Naiteru yoru daita mama
泣いてる夜抱いたまま
Crying and embracing the night
Nageki wo sakende
嘆きを叫んで
Screaming its grief out loud
Nageki wo sakende
嘆きを叫んで
Screaming its grief out loud
Fumiireta ashi wo tooku no risou ga
踏み入れた足を遠くの理想が
The distant ideals gently heal
Fumiireta ashi wo tooku no risou ga
踏み入れた足を遠くの理想が
The distant ideals gently heal
Sotto iyashite yuku
そっと癒してゆく
These legs that've stepped forward
Sotto iyashite yuku
そっと癒してゆく
These legs that've stepped forward
Tashika na kizuna wo tsuyoku nigirisusumou
確かな絆を強く握り進もう
I'll hold on tight to these definite bonds as I advance
Tashika na kizuna wo tsuyoku nigirisusumou
確かな絆を強く握り進もう
I'll hold on tight to these definite bonds as I advance
Dokomade mo
どこまでも
No matter where I go
Dokomade mo
どこまでも
No matter where I go
Kegarekitta kiseki wo se ni
穢れきった奇跡を背に
I'll shoulder these tainted miracles
Kegarekitta kiseki wo se ni
穢れきった奇跡を背に
I'll shoulder these tainted miracles
Year 2
Japanese
Hey!
こらあ
Japanese
Year 2
You're ganging up to make her do things she doesn't like?!
そうやって寄ってたかって人の嫌がることするなんて
You guys suck!
アンタ達最低　最ッ低よ
You really suck!
What's your problem, Tohsaka?
なんだよ　遠坂　お前には関係ねえだろう
This is none of your business.
Well then...
じゃ　私にも同じことしていいわよ
Go ahead and do the same thing to me.
Then it'll be my business, right?
そうすれば　関係あるでしょう
Hey.
おい
ふん　面白くねえ
Boring!
Here.
はい
Year 2
Japanese
You infused too much mana at once.
魔力を一度に注入しすぎたんだ
Keep your mind calm.
平常心を保つこと
In order to control mana, you must first control your mind.
魔力を制御するには自分の精神をコントロールし続けなければいけない
Lose control, and the mana will rebound back to your body.
その制御を誤ると　魔力は自分の体に跳ね返ってきてしまう
Too much power in the wrong form will harm not only you, but those around you as well.
加え過ぎた力　誤った形は自分だけでなく
周りにも害を与える
Strive to consistently maintain the proper flow.
常に正しい流れを心がけなさい
That is the Tohsaka family precept.
それが遠坂家の家訓である
It means to be in control and elegant at all times.
「常に余裕を持って優雅たれ」ということだ
Kotone, you shouldn't keep quiet when they do that stuff.
琴音もああいう時は黙ってちゃダメよ
You need to get mad if they're in the wrong.
あっちが間違ってるなら　ちゃんと怒らないとダメなんだから
Rin-chan, you're amazing.
凛ちゃんはすごいね　あんなにはっきり言えて
You always speak your mind.
That's not true.
そんなことないわよ　普通って言うか　当然って言うか
I think it's normal and natural...
Yes.
そう
It's natural.
当然なのだ
Hold out your hands.
手を出してご覧
Father, teach me more!
お父様　もっと教えてください
How do I make something like this?
これはどうやったら作れますか
Let's see.
そうだな　これは今の凛には難しいかもしれない
It might be too hard for you right now.
But I'm sure you'll be able to make it
eventually if you work hard every day.
でも
凛が毎日努力すれば　きっと作れるようになる
You're the daughter of the Tohsaka family, after all.
なんと言っても　お前は遠坂の娘なのだから
Hey, Rin-chan.
ねえ　凛ちゃん
Can you show me how to do this part?
ここ教えてほしいんだけど　いいかな
Of course. Where?
もちろん　どこ
Me, too!
あ　私も 私も
Me, too.
This was on page 23 in the textbook.
これはね　教科書の23ページに載ってたわ
Topic:  7 Times-Tables
Topic:  Rectangles
You just did the math wrong here.
こっちはここ計算違いしてるだけ
Topic:   Reading and Writing Kanji
As for this question...
この問題は
Elementary School Japanese
Dictionary
Look, it's just like this example.
ほら　ここの例題と一緒なの
すごい
Kotone.
Sit down. I'll help everybody one by one.
ほら　座って　順番に教えるから
Okay!
Do I have to go live with the Zenjou?
やっぱり禅城のお家へ行かなければダメですか
Once the Holy Grail War begins, Fuyuki City will no longer be safe.
聖杯戦争が始まったらここ冬木市は安全とは言えなくなる
Father, I want to help you win the Grail War.
私　お父様が聖杯戦争に勝つのを手伝いたい
Rin, you mustn't cause your father trouble.
凛　お父様を困らせてはダメよ
Are we in the way?
私達は邪魔なの
That's not it.
そうではない
This time, I'll need to make extra preparations to battle under perfect conditions.
今回はいつも以上に万全を期した状態で戦う
Which include securing the safety of you and your mother.
それには　凛たちの身の安全も確保するということも含まれている
And for that, it's better if both of you leave Fuyuki City.
そのために凛達は冬木市でないところに行ったほうがいい
I'm sure there's something I can do to help!
私にだって手伝えることはきっとあるわ
That's right.
そうよ
I just haven't learned how to yet.
まだちゃんと教わってないだけだもの
So all I need to do is study on my own.
それなら　自分で勉強すればいいのよ
I-I don't understand at all...
ぜ　全然分かんない
What is this?!
何よ
Geez!
もう
Du, wer die Tür geöffnet hat, wird Freunde sein.
You, who opened the door, will be friends.
Fur die Aussage nimm meine Hand
I have to close it.
閉じなきゃ
Für die Aussage nimm meine Hand.
For this declaration, take my hand.
Wir werden in meinem Zimmer treffen.
We will meet in my room.
wir weden in meinem Zimmer treffen
Sind deine Arme klein, groß, schlank, steif?
Are your arms small, big, slender, or firm?
It won't move!
動かない
Klein Gross Schlank Steif
Rin!
凛
Jeder ist gleich.
All are the same.
大丈夫か
Are you all right?
It's still too soon for you to read this book.
凛にはまだこの本は早いな
Some things in this world contain their own mana.
この世界には時として それ自体が魔力を帯びているものがある
これは魔力針と言って
This is called a mana compass.
Normally, it doesn't indicate anything.
普段は何の反応も示せないが
But if there are mana traces in the area...
近くに魔力の痕跡があると
Rin, try generating mana in this.
凛　これに魔力を発生させてご覧
Okay.
はい
...it does that.
こんな具合だ
And with that book...
そしてさっきの本は
Anything that causes a reaction like that is beyond your ability, so be careful.
こういう反応するものはまだ凛の手には負えないから　気をつけるように
I'll give this to you.
これは凛にあげよう
As an early birthday present.
少し早い誕生日プレゼントだ
Th-Thank you, Father!
ありがとうございます　お父様
Once the Holy Grail War ends, we'll try some real Jewel Magic.
聖杯戦争が終わったら
もっと本格的な宝石魔術をやってみるとしよう
Then strange occurrences began occurring.
やがて異変は起こり始めた
また自習だって
Study period again, apparently.
Study Period
The morning news was also talking about the kidnappings.
今朝のニュースも誘拐事件だったぜ
News
Serial
Kidnappings
In Fuyuki City, the sudden disappearances of children...
The teachers have been in a meeting all day.
先生たちずっと会議やってるね
Staff Room
In a
Meeting
今日五時間目無しだって
They said we won't have fifth period today!
Notice:
Afternoon Classes Canceled
School News
Beware of
Suspicious-looking People!!
All right!
やった
But they said we should stay at home.
でも　家にいなきゃいけないの
Why?
なんで
Serial
Kidnappings
News
また誘拐事件
Another kidnapping...
They said only children had been kidnapped.
子供ばっか誘拐されてんだよね
Hey, did you hear?
ねえねえ　聞いた
I hear the body isn't inside the coffin.
遺体　中に入れてないらしいですよ
That's... horrible.
状態　よっぽどなんですかね
It definitely happened in Fuyuki, right?
事件があったのは冬木で間違いないんでしょう
U-Um, I'm Kotone-chan's classmate, Tohsaka...
あの　私　琴音ちゃんと同じクラスの遠坂
The person you are calling is not home.
Please leave your message after the beep.
ピーと鳴った後にメッセイジお願いします
無事でいて
Please be safe...
Kotone.
This is Fuyuki at night...
これが　夜の冬木
It's completely different from during the day.
昼間と全然違う
It's really scary.
すごく嫌な感じ
What's this?
何これ
I've never seen it react like this.
こんな反応見たことない
Does that mean there are mana traces all over the place?
そこら中に魔力の痕跡があるっていうの
Request:  Murderings and kidnappings have been occurring frequently
around the area recently. Please refrain from going out at night.
I have to find Kotone!
琴音を探さなくちゃ
Out with a kid this late?
こんな時間に子供連れ
What was that?
何　今の
Oh no!
やばっ
Phew.
よかった
見つかったら 連れ戻されちゃう
They'd take me home if they found me.
ほら ちゃんと歩かないと
Come on, keep walking.
Two of them?
二人
子供が増えてた
He got another kid.
Why?
どうして
だめじゃない
Wait. Why am I hiding?
なんで隠れちゃうのよ
こんなんじゃ何もできない
I can't accomplish anything at this rate!
誰もいない
No one's here?
H-Hey!
ちょっと
Kotone?!
Kotone! Kotone!
何かされてる
Did they do something to her?
どうしよう
What should I do?
何か
Something...
あれ  どうしたの  迷子かな
Huh? Are you lost?
いや あのう
No... Um...
ちょうどいいや
You've come at the right time.
We're just about to start a party.
今から俺らパーティ始めるとこなんだよね
But we still don't have enough people.
でもまだ人手不足でさあ
君も手伝ってくんない
Wanna help too?
ほら こういうのって 皆いた方が盛り上がるじゃん
Come on. The more, the merrier, right?
いやっ
No!
なに 今のは
What was that?
逃げんなよ
Don't you run away.
あのブレスレットで皆を
He's using that bracelet on them?!
Ow!
痛てっ
壊さなきゃ
I have to destroy it!
Oh, so you're gonna help me, after all.
なんだ やっぱり手伝ってくれんじゃん
あれ なに
Huh? What's this?
You infused too much mana at once.
魔力を一度に注入しすぎたんだ
こんなもの
This is nothing!
なんっ…
Kotone!
凛ちゃん
Rin-chan...
Huh? Where am I?
なにここ
泣いてる暇なんかないわよ
There's no time to cry! Run!
逃げるの
Hey! Wait!
おい 待て
Man...
I wonder if Mister'll be mad about this.
旦那に怒られるかな
あれ 凛ちゃんは
Huh?
Where's Rin-chan?
What a relief...
よかった
さあ 帰ろう
I should head back.
I did it, Father.
やったよ お父様
What?
なに
Anything that causes a reaction like that is beyond your ability, so be careful.
こういう反応をするものは
まだ凛の手には負えないから気をつけるように
凛 あの子まさか冬木に行ったなんて
I can't believe Rin went to Fuyuki...
凛
Rin!
Rin...
凛ちゃんは大丈夫 寝てるだけだ
Rin-chan's fine.
She's just sleeping.
Kariya-kun?
雁夜くん
なに どういうことなの
What? What's happening here?
What are you doing here?
どうしてあなたがここに
Your face...
その顔
これが間桐の魔術だよ
This is the magic of the Matou family.
You offer your flesh, and your life is slowly devoured.
肉を捧げ 命を蝕まれ
Our sorcery comes at this price.
それを代価にして至る魔道だ
でも 桜ちゃんは大丈夫
But Sakura-chan is fine.
I'll definitely save her before this happens to her.
こんなことになる前に俺がきっと救い出す
Zouken only desires the Grail.
臓硯が欲しいのは聖杯だけだ
俺がそれを勝ち取れば
He promised to release Sakura-chan if I win it for him.
桜ちゃんを解放すると あいつはそう約束した
The Grail, you said?!
聖杯ですって
ああ 心配ないよ
Yeah, don't worry.
俺のサーヴァントは最強なんだ
My Servant is the strongest.
誰にも負けるはずはない
It won't lose to anyone.
Right now, even hope causes Sakura-chan nothing but pain.
今の桜ちゃんにとっては希望を懐くことさえ
辛い責め苦にしかならない
だから あの子の代わりに祈ってくれ
So pray for me in her stead.
For my victory...
俺の勝利を 桜ちゃんの未来を
And for Sakura-chan's future.
Kariya-kun, you...
雁夜君 あなたは
いつかきっと この公園で また昔みたいに皆で遊べる日が来るから
I'm sure the day will come when we
can all play in this park like we used to.
And Rin-chan and Sakura-chan will go back to being sisters.
凛ちゃんも桜ちゃんも元の姉妹に戻って
だから 葵さん あなたはもう泣かなくていい
So, Aoi-san.
You don't need to cry anymore.
雁夜くん あなたは 死ぬ気なの
Kariya-kun, do you plan to die?
After killing Tokiomi...
時臣を殺して
お母様
Mother?
Rin!
凛
もう心配したんだから
I was so worried!
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry... I'm sorry!
ごめんなさい ごめんなさい
I'm sorry...
綺礼様
Kirei-sama, are you certain you wish to leave
Tohsaka Tokiomi's wife and daughter like this?
遠坂時臣氏のご内儀とご息女をこのまま放置でよろしいか
It's fine.
構わない
Continue monitoring Berserker's Master.
引き続きバーサーカーのマスターを監視するように
承知
Understood.
小さなことだけど 私にもできることがあった
It wasn't much, but I did manage to do something.
だからといって 一人前かというと
But as for whether I'm independent yet, I passed out halfway through, so...
途中で気絶しちゃうなんて
I have a long way to go.
私はまだまだってことだ
でも それは今だけの話
But that's just for now.
私には時間もたっぷりあるわけだし
I have plenty of time, after all.
いつか 遠坂の魔術師として戦う時が来る
Someday, I'll fight as a Tohsaka Mage.
そんなときがいつきてもいいように
So that I'll always be ready, I'll work really hard and uphold my father's teachings.
努力を怠らず
お父様の教えを守り
その時できることを全力で かつ優雅にやっていけばいいんだ
And when the time comes, I'll just do the best I can, elegantly.
Episode 10
Rin's Adventure
Shizuka ni utsuriyuku
Amidst the quietly shifting
静かに移りゆく
Shizuka ni utsuriyuku
Amidst the quietly shifting
静かに移りゆく
Tooi kioku no naka
Distant memories
遠い記憶の中
Tooi kioku no naka
Distant memories
遠い記憶の中
Omoide ni yorisoinagara
If I can find peace in my recollections
思い出に寄り添いながら
Omoide ni yorisoinagara
If I can find peace in my recollections
思い出に寄り添いながら
Kimi wo omoeru nara
While reminiscing about you
君を想えるなら
Kimi wo omoeru nara
While reminiscing about you
君を想えるなら
Itsumo minareteru madobe ni utsutta
I am all too familiar with the window reflection
いつも見慣れてる窓辺に映った
Itsumo minareteru madobe ni utsutta
I am all too familiar with the window reflection
いつも見慣れてる窓辺に映った
Sono hitomi wa ashita wo muite ita
Of your eyes that were gazing into the future
その瞳は明日を向いていた
Sono hitomi wa ashita wo muite ita
Of your eyes that were gazing into the future
その瞳は明日を向いていた
Ah sakaraenu sadame to shitte mo
Ah, even though I know there's no escaping this fate
あぁ 逆らえぬ運命と知っても
Ah sakaraenu sadame to shitte mo
Ah, even though I know there's no escaping this fate
あぁ 逆らえぬ運命と知っても
Kowakunai kokoro kara shinjite iru
I'm not afraid. I have faith from the bottom of my heart
怖くない 心から信じている
Kowakunai kokoro kara shinjite iru
I'm not afraid. I have faith from the bottom of my heart
怖くない 心から信じている
Shizuka ni utsuriyuku
Amidst the quietly shifting
静かに移りゆく
Shizuka ni utsuriyuku
Amidst the quietly shifting
静かに移りゆく
Tooi kioku no naka
Distant memories
遠い記憶の中
Tooi kioku no naka
Distant memories
遠い記憶の中
Kimi to sugoshita akashi wa
Proof of the time I spent with you
君と過ごした証は
Kimi to sugoshita akashi wa
Proof of the time I spent with you
君と過ごした証は
Tashika ni koko ni aru
Is right here with me
確かにここにある
Tashika ni koko ni aru
Is right here with me
確かにここにある
Afuredasu kimochi wo
You've shown me what it means
溢れ出す気持ちを
Afuredasu kimochi wo
You've shown me what it means
溢れ出す気持ちを
Oshiete kureta kara
To have overflowing feelings
教えてくれたから
Oshiete kureta kara
To have overflowing feelings
教えてくれたから
Kono sekai ga nakunatte mo
Even if this world were to end
この世界がなくなっても
Kono sekai ga nakunatte mo
Even if this world were to end
この世界がなくなっても
Watashi wa soko ni iru
I'll be right by your side
私はそこにいる
Watashi wa soko ni iru
I'll be right by your side
私はそこにいる
無欲な王など飾り物にも劣るわい
A king without greed is even worse than a figurehead!
Of what worth is a king who fails to protect the powerless?
力無きものを守らずしてどうする
We have nothing to lose.
我々が失うものは何も無い
A Reality Marble?!
固有結界ですって
I shall kill you myself.
貴様はこのオレが手ずから殺す
Wasn't your goal supposed to be world conquest-
望みは世界征服だった
Next Episode
Grail Dialogue